Hello, my name is Jill Weiss, and I'm going to tell you a little bit about how to play shortstop.
First thing you want to remember, is that the shortstop is one of those positions, where you've got to be a lot of places.
You've got to be thinking all the time, and you could be covering second base.
You could be covering first base.
You could be catching a fly ball, into the outfield.
You could be charging a slap, a bunt, but you've always got to be communicating.
That's the most important thing.
Communicating with your second basemen, on who's covering.
Communicating with your third basemen, in case there's a steal.
Communicating with your catcher, communicating with your pitcher, things like that.
The shortstop is one of those positions, where they are probably one of the strongest arms on the field.
They have to cross, throwing from shortstop, all the way to first base. They have to be agile. They have to be quick.
They've got to be moving on their feet, constantly moving, and constantly thinking two plays ahead.
Always, ok there's a runner on second, what am I going to do, if this ball is hit to me?
situations like that.
When you are fielding the ball, you always want to get in front of it.
Look at it all the way in.
Use two hands, if you have to, things like that.
Just remember, as a shortstop, that you've always got to be thinking.
My name is Jill Weiss, and those are just a few tips on how to be a shortstop.